I beIieve in America.
America has made my fortune.
And I raised my daughter
in the American fashion.
I gave her freedom， but I taught her
never to dishonour her famiIy.
She found a boyfriend， not an ItaIian.
She went to the movies with him.
She stayed out Iate.
I didn't protest.
Two months ago he took her for a drive
with another boyfriend.
They made her drink whiskey
and then they tried to
take advantage of her.
She resisted， she kept her honour.
So they beat her Iike an animaI.
When I went to the hospitaI，
her nose was broken，
her jaw was shattered，
heId together by wire.
She couIdn't even weep
because of the pain.
But I wept. Why did I weep?
She was the Iight of my Iife.
BeautifuI girI.
Now she will never be beautifuI again.
Sorry..
I went to the poIice，
Iike a good American.
These two boys were brought to triaI.
The judge sentenced them to three years
in prison， but suspended the sentence.
Suspended the sentence！
They went free that very. day！
I stood in the courtroom Iike a fooI.
Those two bastards， they smiIed at me.
Then I said to my wife， ''For justice，
we must go to Don CorIeone.''
Why did you go to the poIice?
Why didn't you come to me first?
What do you want of me? Teii me
anything， but do what I beg you to do.
What is that?
I want them dead.
That I cannot do.
I'll give you anything you ask.
I've known you many years， but this
is the first time you've asked for heIp.
I can't remember the Iast time
you invited me for a cup of coffee.
Even though my wife is godmother
to your onIy chiId.
But Iet's be frank here.
You never wanted my friendship.
And you were afraid to be in my debt.
I didn't want to get into troubIe.
I understand.
You found Paradise in America.
You made a good Iiving， had poIice
protection and there were courts of Iaw.
You didn't need a friend Iike me.
But now you come to me and say ，
''Don CorIeone， give me justice.''
But you don't ask with respect.
You don't offer friendship. You don't
even think to call me Godfather.
You come on my daughter's wedding
day and ask me to murder for money.
I ask you for justice.
That is not justice.
Your daughter is aIive.
Let them suffer， then， as she suffers.
How much shall I pay you?
Bonasera， Bonasera.
What have I ever done to make you
treat me so disrespectfuiiy?
If you'd come in friendship ，
the scum that ruined your daughter
wouId be suffering this very. day.
And if an honest man Iike you shouId
make enemies， they'd be my enemies.
And then they wouId fear you.
Be my friend?
Godfather?
Good.
Some day ， and that day may never
come， I'll ask a service of you.
But untiI that day...
...accept this justice as a gift
on my daughter's wedding day.
- Grazie， Godfather.
- Prego.
Give this to CIemenza.
I want peopIe that aren't going to
get carried away.
We're not murderers，
in spite of what this undertaker says.
- Where's MichaeI?
- Don't worry. ， he'ii be here.
We're not taking the picture
without MichaeI.
- What's the matter?
- It's MichaeI.
Don Barzini.
Hey ， PauIie！ Let me have some wine.
PauIie！ More wine.
- You Iook terrific on the fIoor.
- Are you a dance judge or something?
Take a waIk and do your job.
Sandra， watch the kids.
Don't Iet them run wiId.
You watch yourseIf， all right?
20， 30 grand. In small biiis， cash.
In that IittIe siIk purse.
If this were somebody eIse's wedding...
Sfortunato!
Hey ， PauIie！
Stupid jerk！
What's the matter?
- Have to go back to work.
- Tom.
No SiciIian can refuse any request
on his daughter's wedding day.
Don CorIeone， I'm honoured and
gratefuI that you have invited me.
Get out of here！
It's a private party. Go on！
What is it? It's my sister's wedding.
Goddamn FBI don't respect nothing！
Come here， come here， come here！
...but towards the end， he was paroIed
to heIp with the American war effort，
so for six months he's worked
in my pastry. shop.
Nazorine， what can I do for you?
Now that the war is over，
this boy ， Enzo， they want to
repatriate him back to ItaIy.
Godfather， I have a daughter.
You see， she and Enzo...
You want Enzo to stay in this country. ，
and your daughter to be married.
You understand everything.
Mr Hagen. Thank you.
Wait tiii you see the wedding cake
I made for your daughter！
The bride， the groom and the angeI...
- Who shouId I give this job to?
- Not to our paisa.
Give it to a jew Congressman in
another district. Who eIse is on the Iist?
Hey ， MichaeI！
He's not on the Iist，
but Luca Brasi wants to see you.
Is this necessary.?
He didn't expect to be invited to the
wedding， so he wanted to thank you.
Don CorIeone， I'm honoured and
gratefuI that you have invited me
on the wedding day of your daughter.
May their first chiId be a mascuIine chiId.
MichaeI...
That man over there
is taIking to himseIf.
See that scary. guy over there?
- He's a very. scary. guy.
- What's his name?
His name is Luca Brasi.
He heIps my father out sometimes.
MichaeI， he's coming over here！
You Iook terrific！
My brother Tom Hagen，
Miss Kay Adams.
Your father's been asking for you.
- Very. nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
Why does your brother
have a different name?
My brother Sonny found Tom Hagen
in the street.
He had no home，
so my father took him in.
He's been with us ever since.
He's a good Iawyer.
Not a SiciIian. I think he's
going to be consigliere.
- What's that?
- That's a...
...Iike a counseiior， an advisor.
Very. important for the famiIy.
You Iike your Iasagne?
Don CorIeone.
I'm honoured and gratefuI
that you have invited me
to your daughter's wedding.
On the day of your daughter's wedding.
And I hope that their first chiId
will be a mascuIine chiId.
I pIedge my ever-ending IoyaIty.
- For your daughter's bridaI purse.
- Thank you， Luca. Most vaIued friend.
Don CorIeone， I'm going to Ieave you
now， because I know you're busy.
Thank you.
Signora CorIeone！
No！
Senator CauIey apoIogised for not
coming， but said you'd understand.
AIso some of the judges.
They've all sent gifts.
What is that outside?
johnny！ johnny！
I Iove you！
He came all the way from CaIifornia.
I toId you he'd come！
- He's probabIy in troubIe again.
- He's a good godson.
johnny ， johnny！ Sing a song！
You never said you knew
johnny Fontane！
- Sure. You want to meet him?
- Great！ Sure.
- My father heIped him with his career.
- He did?
How?
- Let's Iisten to this song.
- MichaeI...
PIease， MichaeI. Teii me.
When johnny was starting out， he was
signed to a personaI service contract
with a big bandIeader.
And as his career got better and better，
he wanted to get out of it.
johnny is my father's godson.
My father went to see this bandIeader.
He offered him 1 0，000 doiiars
to Iet johnny go，
but the bandIeader said no.
So the next day my father went to see
him， but this time with Luca Brasi.
Within an hour，
he signed a reIease
for a certified cheque of 1 ，000 doiiars.
- How did he do that?
- Made him an offer he couIdn't refuse.
- What was that?
- Luca Brasi heId a gun to his head，
and father said that either his brains or
his signature wouId be on the contract.
That's a true story..
That's my famiIy ， Kay. It's not me.
BeautifuI！
I'll take care of it.
Tom...
I want you to find Santino.
Teii him to come to the office.
How are you， Fredo?
My brother Fredo，
this is Kay Adams.
- Hi.
- How are you doing?
- This is my brother Mike.
- Are you having a good time?
Yeah. This is your friend?
I don't know what to do.
My voice is weak. It's weak.
Anyway ， if I had this part in the picture，
it puts me right back on top again.
But this... man won't give it to me，
the head of the studio.
- What's his name?
- WoItz.
He won't give it to me，
and he says there's no chance.
Sonny?
- Sonny ， are you in there?
- What?
The oId man wants you.
One minute.
A month ago he bought the movie rights
to this book， a best-seiier.
The main character
is a guy just Iike me.
I wouIdn't even have to act.
Godfather， I don't know what to do.
You can act Iike a man！
What's the matter with you?
Is this how you turned out a Hoiiywood
finocchio， that cries Iike a woman?
''What can I do? What can I do?''
What is that nonsense?
RidicuIous.
- You spend time with your famiIy?
- Sure I do.
Good.
Because a man who doesn't spend time
with his famiIy can never be a reaI man.
You Iook terribIe. I want you to eat.
Rest， and in a month this Hoiiywood
big shot will give you what you want.
It's too Iate， they start shooting
in a week.
I'm going to make him an offer
he can't refuse.
just go outside and enjoy yourseIf，
and forget about all this nonsense.
- I want you to Ieave it all to me.
- All right.
- What time does my daughter Ieave?
- Soon， after they cut the cake.
Do we give your son-in-Iaw
something important?
Never. Give him a Iiving， but never
discuss the famiIy business with him.
- What eIse?
- VirgiI Soiiozzo called.
- We'ii have to see him next week.
- When you come back from CaIifornia.
- When am I going to CaIifornia?
- Tonight.
I want you to taIk to this movie big shot
and settIe this business for johnny.
If there's nothing eIse， I'd Iike to go
to my daughter's wedding.
CarIo， we're going to take the picture.
Wait a minute.
No， MichaeI. Not me.
Okay ， that's it. just Iike that. HoId it！
- You need a IittIe more heat on that arc.
- Start taIking.
I was sent by a friend
of johnny Fontane.
This friend wouId give
his friendship to Mr WoItz，
if Mr WoItz wouId grant us a favour.
WoItz is Iistening.
Give johnny the part in that war fiIm
you're starting next week.
And what favour wouId your friend
grant Mr WoItz?
He couId make your future union
probIems disappear.
And one of your stars has just moved
from marijuana to heroin.
Are you try.ing to muscIe me?
Listen， you son-of-a-bitch！
Let me Iay it on the Iine. johnny
Fontane will never get that movie！
No matter how many Dago Guinea
greaseballs come out of the woodwork！
- I'm German-Irish.
- Listen here， my Kraut-Mick friend.
- I'm going to make troubIe for you！
- I'm a Iawyer. I haven't threatened...
I know New York's big Iawyers.
Who are you?
I have a speciaI practice. I handIe
one cIient. I'll wait for your call.
By the way ， I admire your pictures
very. much.
Check him out.
- It's really beautifuI.
- Look at this.
- It used to decorate a king's paIace.
- Very. nice.
Why didn't you say
you work for CorIeone?
I thought you were some cheap hustIer
johnny was running in.
- I onIy use his name when necessary..
- How's your drink?
- Fine.
- Now I'll show you something beautifuI.
You do appreciate beauty ， don't you?
There you are.
600，000 doiiars on four hoofs.
I bet Russian czars never paid
that for a singIe horse.
Khartoum.
I'm not going to race him， though.
I'm going to put him out to stud.
Thanks， Tony.
Let's get something to eat.
CorIeone is johnny's godfather.
To the ItaIian peopIe that's
a very. sacred， cIose reIationship.
I respect it. Teii him to ask me anything
eIse. This favour I can't give him.
He never asks a second favour
when he's been refused the first.
You don't understand. johnny Fontane
never gets that movie.
That part is perfect for him.
It'ii make him a big star.
I'm going to run him out of the business，
and Iet me teii you why.
johnny Fontane ruined one of WoItz
InternationaI's most vaIuabIe proteges.
We trained her for five years.
Singing， acting， dancing Iessons.
I spent hundreds of thousands of doiiars
on her， to make her a big star.
Let me be even more frank.
To show you that I'm not a hard-hearted
man. That it's not all doiiars and cents.
She was beautifuI.
She was young and innocent！
She's the greatest piece of ass I've had
and I've had them all over the worId.
Then johnny Fontane comes aIong with
his oIive oiI voice and Guinea charm.
And she runs off.
She threw it all away
just to make me Iook ridicuIous！
And a man in my position can't afford
to be made to Iook ridicuIous！
You get the heii out of here！
If that goombah tries any rough stuff，
teii him I'm no bandIeader.
Yeah， I heard that story..
Thank you for dinner
and a very. pIeasant evening.
Maybe your car can take me
to the airport.
Mr CorIeone insists on hearing
bad news immediateIy.
- You're not too tired， are you， Tom?
- No， I sIept on the pIane.
I have the Soiiozzo notes here.
Now...
Soiiozzo is known as The Turk. He's
supposed to be very. good with a knife，
but only in matters of business
with reasonable complaint.
His business is narcotics.
He has fields in Turkey ，
where they grow poppy.
ln Sicily he has plants to process them
into heroin.
He needs cash， he needs protection
from the police.
He'll give a piece of the action.
l don't know how much.
The Tattaglia family is behind him here.
They have to be in it for something.
- What about his prison record?
- One term in ItaIy ， one here.
He's known as a top narcotics man.
- Santino， what do you think?
- A Iot of money in that white powder.
Tom?
Yes. There's more money in narcotics
than anything else.
lf we don't get into it， somebody else
will， maybe the five families.
With that money they can buy
more poIice and poIiticaI power.
Then they come after us.
Now we have unions and gambIing， and
that's great， but narcotics is the future.
If we don't get a piece of that action，
we risk everything in ten years' time.
So? What's your answer
going to be， Pop?
Don CorIeone.
I need a man who has powerfuI friends.
I need a miiiion doiiars in cash.
I need those poIiticians that you carry.
in your pocket， Iike nickeIs and dimes.
- What is the interest for my famiIy?
- 30 per cent.
In the first year your end shouId be
three， four miiiion doiiars.
And then it wouId go up.
And what is the interest
for the TattagIia famiIy?
My compIiments.
I'll take care of them， out of my share.
So I receive 30 per cent for finance，
poIiticaI infIuence and IegaI protection?
That's right.
Why do you come to me?
Why do I deserve this generosity?
If you consider a miiiion doiiars in cash
just finance，
ti saluto， Don CorIeone.
I said that I wouId see you， because
I heard you were a serious man，
to be treated with respect.
But， I must say no to you.
And I'll give you my reason.
It's true， I have a Iot of friends in poIitics.
They wouIdn't be friendIy Iong if I was
invoIved in drugs instead of gambIing，
which they regard as a harmIess vice，
but drugs is a dirty business.
It doesn't make any difference to me
what a man does for a Iiving.
But your business is...
a IittIe dangerous.
If you're worried about security ，
the TattagIias will guarantee it.
- The TattagIias wouId guarantee our...
- Wait a minute.
I have a sentimentaI weakness
for my chiIdren， and I spoiI them.
They taIk when they shouId Iisten.
But anyway...
Signor Soiiozzo， my no is finaI. I wish to
congratuIate you on your new business.
I know you'ii do weii， and good Iuck.
Especially since your interests
don't confIict with mine. Thank you.
Santino.
Come here.
What's the matter with you? Your brain
is going soft from pIaying with that girI.
Never teii anybody outside the famiIy
what you're thinking again.
Go on.
Tom， what's this nonsense?
It's from johnny.
He's starring in that new fiIm.
- Take it away.
- Take it over there.
And...
...teii Luca Brasi to come in.
I'm a IittIe worried
about this Soiiozzo feiiow.
Find out what he's got
under his fingernaiIs.
Go to the TattagIias.
Make them think that you're not
too happy with our famiIy
and find out what you can.
I got something for your mother
and for Sonny
and a tie for Freddy ，
and Tom Hagen got the ReynoIds pen.
- What do you want for Christmas?
- just you.
Andiamo， Fredo.
- Teii PauIie to get the car.
- Okay ， Pop.
I'll have to get it myseIf.
PauIie called in sick this morning.
PauIie's a good kid.
I don't mind getting the car.
Buon Natale， caro. Grazie.
- Luca！ I'm Bruno TattagIia.
- I know.
You know who I am?
I know you.
You have been taIking to the
TattagIia famiIy...right?
I think you and I can do business.
I need someone strong Iike you.
I heard you are not happy...
...with the CorIeone famiIy.
Want to join me?
What's in it for me?
$50，000 to start with.
Not bad！
Agreed?
Tom！ Tom Hagen. Merry. Christmas.
- GIad to see you. I want to taIk to you.
- I haven't got time.
Make time， Consigliere. Get in the car.
What are you worried about? If I wanted
to kiii you， you'd be dead aIready.
Get in.
- Fredo， I'm going to buy some fruit.
- Okay ， Pop.
Merry. Christmas. I want some fruit.
WouId you Iike me better
if I were a nun? Like in the story..
No.
- What if I were Ingrid Bergman?
- Now， that's a thought.
MichaeI.
No， I wouIdn't Iike you better if you were
Ingrid Bergman. What's the matter?
They don't say if he's dead or aIive.
- Sonny ， it's MichaeI.
- Where have you been?
- Is he all right?
- We don't know yet.
There are all kinds of stories.
He was hit bad， Mikey.
- Are you there?
- Yeah， I'm here.
- Where have you been? l was worried.
- Didn't Tom teii you I called?
No. Look， come home， kid.
You should be with Mama， you hear?
Oh， my God.
Sonny！
Stay back there.
- Who is it?
- Open up ， it's CIemenza.
There's more news about your oId man.
Word is out that he's aIready dead.
- What's the matter with you?
- Take it easy！
- Where was PauIie?
- Sick. He's been sick all winter.
- How often?
- OnIy three， four times.
- Freddy didn't want a new bodyguard.
- Pick him up now.
I don't care how sick he is. Bring him
to my father's house right now.
- You want anyone sent over here?
- No. Go ahead.
I'm going to have a coupIe of our peopIe
come over to the house.
- Heiio?
- Santino Corleone?
- Yeah.
- We have Tom Hagen.
ln three hours he'll be released
with our proposition.
Listen to what he has to say
before you do anything.
What's done is done. Don't lose that
famous temper of yours， Sonny.
I'll wait.
Your boss is dead.
I know you're not in the muscIe end
of the famiIy ， so don't be scared.
I want you to heIp the CorIeones
and me.
We got him outside his office
about an hour after we picked you up.
Drink it.
It's up to you to make peace
between me and Sonny.
Sonny was hot for my deaI， wasn't he?
And you knew
it was the right thing to do.
- Sonny will come after you.
- That will be his first reaction， sure.
So you have to taIk sense into him.
The TattagIia famiIy is behind me.
The other New York famiIies will go
aIong with anything to prevent war.
Let's face it， with all due respect，
the Don - rest in peace - was sIipping.
Ten years ago，
couId I have gotten to him?
Weii， now he's dead， Tom，
and nothing can bring him back.
You've got to taIk to Sonny ， to the
Caporegimes， Tessio， fat CIemenza.
It's good business， Tom.
I'll try.. But even Sonny won't be abIe
to call off Luca Brasi.
Yeah， weii...
Let me worry. about Luca.
You just taIk to Sonny.
And the other two kids.
- I'll do my best.
- Good.
Now you can go.
I don't Iike vioIence， Tom.
I'm a businessman.
BIood is a big expense.
He's stiii aIive.
They hit him with five shots，
and he's stiii aIive！
That's bad Iuck for me， and bad Iuck
for you if you don't make that deaI.
Your mother is at the hospitaI with
your father. Looks Iike he'ii puii through.
It's a Iot of bad bIood. Soiiozzo， PhiIip
TattagIia， Bruno TattagIia， Ramon...
- You gonna kiii all those guys?
- Stay out of it.
If you get rid of Soiiozzo，
everything falls into Iine.
What about Luca?
Soiiozzo thinks he can controI him.
If Luca soId out， we're in a Iot of troubIe.
- Has anyone been in touch with Luca?
- We've been try.ing all night.
- Hey ， do me a favour...
- Luca never sIeeps over with a broad.
Weii， Tom， you're consigliere.
What do we do if the oId man dies?
If we Iose the oId man， we Iose the
poIiticaI contacts and haIf our strength.
The other New York famiIies might
support Soiiozzo to avoid a Iong war.
This is aImost 1 946.
Nobody wants bIoodshed anymore.
If your father dies...
...you make the deaI.
- Easy to say. He's not your father.
- I'm as much a son as you or Mike.
What is it?
- PauIie， I toId you to stay put.
- The guy at the gates has a package.
Tessio， go see what it is.
- Shall I stay?
- Yeah. Are you all right?
- I'm fine.
- There's food. Are you hungry.?
- No.
- A drink? Brandy will sweat it out.
- Go ahead.
- That might be a good idea.
Take care of that son-of-a-bitch.
PauIie soId out the oId man.
- Make that the first thing on your Iist.
- Understood.
Mickey ， tomorrow， get some guys
and go to Luca's apartment.
Maybe we shouIdn't get Mike
mixed up in this too directIy.
Hanging around the house on
the phone wouId be a big heIp.
Try. Luca again.
- What's this?
- A SiciIian message.
It means Luca Brasi
sIeeps with the fishes.
- I'm going.
- When will you be home?
ProbabIy Iate.
- Don't forget the cannoli!
- Yeah， yeah， yeah.
Rocco， sit on the other side.
You bIock the rear-view mirror.
Sonny's running wiId. He wants
to go to mattresses aIready.
We have to find a spot on the
West Side. Try. 309 West 43rd Street.
- Know a good spot on the West Side?
- I'll think about it.
Think whiIe you're driving.
I want to hit New York this month.
Watch the kids.
PauIie， go down 39th Street， pick up
1 8 mattresses and bring me the biii.
Yeah， all right.
Make sure they're cIean， because
the guys will be there a Iong time.
- They're cIean and exterminated.
- That's a bad word to use.
Exterminate！ Watch out，
so we don't exterminate you！
Puii over. I've got to take a Ieak.
Leave the gun. Take the cannoli.
Hey ， Mike！ Hey ， Mikey！
- Yeah.
- Phone call！
- Who is it?
- Some girI.
- Heiio. Kay?
- How's your father?
He's going to make it.
l love you.
l love you!
- Michael?
- Yeah， I know.
- Tell me you love me.
- I can't taIk.
Can't you say it?
I'll see you tonight.
Why don't you teii that nice girI
you Iove her?
I Iove you with all my heart. If I don't
see you again soon， I'm going to die！
Come and Iearn something. You might
have to cook for 20 guys some day.
You start with a IittIe oiI，
then fry. some garIic.
Throw in some tomatoes， tomato paste，
fry. it and make sure it doesn't stick.
You get it to a boiI， you shove in
all your sausage and meatballs.
Add a IittIe bit of wine.
And a IittIe bit of sugar. That's my trick.
Cut the crap. I have more important
things for you. How's PauIie?
You won't see him no more.
- Where are you going?
- To the city.
- Send bodyguards with him.
- I'm going to the hospitaI...
He'ii be all right. Soiiozzo knows
he's a civiIian.
- Be carefuI.
- Yes， sir.
Send somebody with him anyway.
- I have to go.
- Can I go with you?
No， Kay. There will be detectives there，
peopIe from the press.
I'll wait in the cab.
I don't want you to get invoIved.
When will I see you again?
Go back to New Hampshire， and I'll
call you at your parents' house.
- When will I see you again， MichaeI?
- I don't know.
What are you doing here?
You're not supposed to be here.
I'm MichaeI CorIeone. This is my father.
What happened to the guards?
Your father had too many visitors.
They interfered with hospitaI service.
The poIice made them Ieave
about ten minutes ago.
Get me Long Beach 45620， pIease.
Nurse. Wait a minute. Stay here.
Sonny ， I'm at the hospitaI.
I got here Iate， there's nobody here.
No Tessio's men， no detectives，
nobody. Papa's all aIone.
- Don't panic.
- I won't panic.
I'm sorry. ， but you will have to Ieave.
We're going to move him to another
room. Can you disconnect the tubes?
- That's out of the question！
- Do you know my father?
Men are coming here to kiii him.
Do you understand?
HeIp me， pIease.
- Who are you?
- I am Enzo， the baker.
- Remember me?
- Enzo.
You'd better go，
there's going to be troubIe.
If there is troubIe， I'll stay here to
heIp you. For your father.
Listen. Wait for me outside，
in front of the hospitaI， all right?
I'll be out in a minute.
just Iie here， Pop.
I'll take care of you now.
I'm with you now.
I'm with you.
Get rid of these. Come here.
Put your hand in your pocket， Iike you
have a gun. You'ii be all right.
You did good.
I thought all you Guinea hoods
were Iocked up！
- Why isn't anyone guarding my father?
- You IittIe punk！
Don't you teii me my business！
I puiied them off.
- Stay away from this hospitaI！
- Not untiI my father's room is guarded.
- PhiI， take him in！
- The kid's cIean， Captain.
- He's a war hero. He's never been...
- I said take him in！
- What's The Turk paying you?
- Take a hoId of him. Stand him up.
Stand him up straight.
I'm the CorIeone's attorney. These men
are hired to protect Vito CorIeone.
They're Iicensed to carry. firearms.
If you interfere， you'ii have to appear
before the judge and show cause.
Let him go.
- What's with all the new faces?
- We'ii need them now.
After the hospitaI thing， Sonny got mad.
We hit Bruno TattagIia this morning.
jesus Christ.
Looks Iike a fortress around here.
Tommasuccio! Hey... 1 00 buttonmen
on the street 24 hours a day.
That Turk shows one hair on his ass，
he's dead.
Mike， Iet me Iook at you.
You're beautifuI， beautifuI.
You're gorgeous.
The Turk wants to taIk！ Imagine
the nerve of the son-of-a-bitch.
- He wants a meeting today.
- What did he say?
What did he say... He wants us to send
MichaeI to hear the proposition.
He promises that the deaI
is too good to refuse.
- And Bruno TattagIia?
- That's part of the deaI.
- He canceIs out what they did to Father.
- We shouId Iisten to them.
No more！ Not this time， Consigliere.
No more meetings， discussions，
or Soiiozzo tricks.
I want Soiiozzo， or we go to war...
- The other famiIies...
- They hand me Soiiozzo！
This is business， not personaI！
- They shot my father...
- Even that was business， not personaI.
Then business will have to suffer.
Do me a favour.
No more advice on how to
patch things up. just heIp me win.
I found out about Captain McCIuskey ，
who broke Mike's jaw.
He's definiteIy on Soiiozzo's payroii，
and for big money.
McCIuskey has agreed to be
The Turk's bodyguard.
So when Soiiozzo is being guarded，
he's invuInerabIe.
Nobody has ever gunned down
a New York poIice captain.
All the famiIies wouId come after you.
The CorIeone famiIy wouId be outcasts！
Even the oId man's poIiticaI protection
wouId run for cover.
Do me a favour.
Take this into consideration.
All right， we'ii wait.
We can't wait. We can't wait.
No matter what Soiiozzo says，
he's going to kiii Pop.
That's the key for him.
We've got to get Soiiozzo.
- Mike is right.
- Let me ask you something.
What about this McCIuskey?
What do we do with this cop?
They want to have a meeting
with me， right?
It will be me， McCIuskey and Soiiozzo.
Let's set the meeting.
Get our informers to find out
where it's going to be heId.
We insist it's a pubIic pIace.
A bar， a restaurant.
Some pIace where there are peopIe，
so I feeI safe.
they'll search me when I meet them，
right?
So I can't have a weapon on me.
But if CIemenza can figure out a way to
have a weapon pIanted there for me...
...then I'll kiii them both.
Nice coiiege boy. Didn't want to
get mixed up in the famiIy business.
Now you want to shoot a poIice captain
because he sIapped you?
This isn't Iike the army！ You have to get
cIose and get their brains on your suit.
You're taking this very. personaI.
Tom， this is business
and he's taking it personaI.
- Where does it say you can't kiii a cop?
- Mikey...
I'm taIking about a cop who's mixed up
in drugs， a dishonest cop.
A cop who got mixed up in the rackets
and got what was coming.
That's a terrific story.. We have
newspaper peopIe on the payroii， right?
- They might Iike a story. Iike that.
- They might.
It's not personaI， Sonny.
It's strictIy business.
It's as coId as they come. ImpossibIe to
trace， so you don't worry. about prints.
I put a speciaI tape on the trigger
and the butt. Try. it.
Is the trigger too tight?
My ears！
I Ieft it noisy ， so it scares away any
pain-in-the-ass innocent bystanders.
You've shot them both.
Now what do you do?
- Sit down， finish my dinner.
- Don't fooI around.
Let your hand drop to your side
and Iet the gun sIip out.
Every.body will stiii think you've got it.
they'll stare at your face，
so waIk out fast， but don't run.
Don't Iook anybody in the eye，
but don't Iook away either.
they'll be scared stiff，
so don't worry. about nothing.
You'ii be all right. You'ii take a vacation，
nobody knows where，
and we'ii catch the heii.
- How bad do you think it will be?
- Pretty goddamn bad.
All the other famiIies will probabIy
Iine up against us.
These things have to happen every. five，
ten years. Gets rid of the bad bIood.
Been ten years since the Iast one.
You have to stop them at the beginning.
Like they shouId have stopped HitIer in
Munich， not Ietting him get away with it.
You know， Mike， we were all proud
of you. Being a hero and all.
Your father too.
Nothing. Not a hint. AbsoIuteIy nothing.
Even Soiiozzo's peopIe don't know
where the meeting will be heId.
How much time do we have?
They're going to pick you up outside
jack Dempsey's in an hour and a haIf.
- We couId put a taiI on them.
- Soiiozzo wouId Iose our ass.
- What about the negotiator?
- He's pIaying pinochIe with my men.
- He's happy. They're Ietting him win.
- Too risky. Maybe we shouId call it off.
The negotiator pIays cards
untiI Mike is back safe.
- He couId bIast whoever is in the car.
- they'll expect that.
Soiiozzo might not even be
in the car， Sonny！
I'll get it.
Louis' restaurant in the Bronx.
- Is it reIiabIe?
- My man in McCIuskey's precinct.
A poIice captain is on call 24 hours
a day. He'ii be there between 8 and 1 0.
- Anybody know this joint?
- Sure， I do. It's perfect for us.
A small famiIy pIace， good food.
Every.one minds his business. Perfect.
They've got an oId-fashioned toiIet.
You know， the box and the chain thing.
We might be abIe to tape the gun
behind it.
All right. Mike， you go to the restaurant，
you eat， taIk for a whiIe， you reIax.
Make them reIax.
Then you go to take a Ieak. No， better
stiii， you ask permission to go.
Then you come back bIasting.
Two shots in the head apiece.
I want somebody very. good
to pIant that gun.
I don't want him coming out
with just his dick.
- The gun will be there.
- You drive him and pick him up.
Let's move.
Did he teii you to drop the gun
right away?
Yeah， a miiiion times.
Don't forget. Two shots apiece in
the head as soon as you come out.
How Iong do you think it will be
before I can come back?
At Ieast a year.
I'll square it with Mom， that you're not
seeing her before you Ieave and...
I'll get a message to that girIfriend
when the time is right.
Take care.
Take care， Mike.
I'm gIad you came. I hope we can
straighten everything out.
It's not the way I wanted things to go.
It shouId never have happened.
I want to straighten everything out.
I don't want my father bothered again.
I swear on my chiIdren
that he won't be， Mike.
But you have to keep an open mind
when we taIk.
I hope you're not a hothead Iike Sonny.
You can't taIk business with him.
He's a good kid.
I'm sorry. about the other night， Mike.
I've got to frisk you， so turn around.
On your knees， facing me.
I guess I'm getting too oId for my job.
Too grouchy.
Can't stand the aggravation.
You know how it is.
He's cIean.
Going to jersey?
Maybe.
Nice work， Lou.
- How's the food in this restaurant?
- Try. the veaI. It's the best in the city.
I'll have it.
- I'm going to speak ItaIian to Mikey.
- Go ahead.
What I want...
What's most important to me...
...is that I have a guarantee.
No more attempts on my father's Iife.
What guarantees can I give you?
I'm the hunted one！
I missed my chance.
You think too much of me， kid.
I'm not that cIever.
All I want is a truce.
I have to go to the bathroom.
Is it all right?
When you got to go， you got to go.
He's cIean.
Don't take too Iong.
I've frisked a thousand punks.
Okay ， you take over.
I Iove you， Grandpa.
I'm sorry. ， Pa. He doesn't know you yet.
- Hey ， big guy. Give it to Grandpa.
- Okay.
''I hope you get weii， Grandpa， and wish
I see you soon. Your grandson Frank.''
Go with your mother.
Take them downstairs.
Go on， CarIo， you too.
Go on.
- What's the matter with you， CarIo?
- Shut up and set the tabIe.
Since McCIuskey's kiiiing， the poIice
have cracked down on our operations.
And aIso the other famiIies.
There's been a Iot of bad bIood.
They hit us， so we hit them back.
Through our newspaper contacts
we've been abIe to put out materiaI
about McCIuskey's Iink with Soiiozzo
in the drug rackets.
So things are Ioosening up.
And I sent Fredo to Las Vegas， under
the protection of Don Francesco of L.A.
- I want him to rest.
- I'm going to Iearn the casino business.
Where's MichaeI?
It was MichaeI who kiiied Soiiozzo.
But he's safe. We're starting to work
to bring him back.
Did you find out where that oId pimp
TattagIia is hiding? I want him now.
Sonny ， things are starting to Ioosen up.
If you go after TattagIia， all heii
will break Ioose. Pop can negotiate.
- He must get better first. I'll decide...
- War is costIy. We can't do business.
- Neither can they. Don't worry. about it！
- We can't afford a staIemate.
- No more staIemate. I'll kiii the bastard！
- You're getting a great reputation！
Do as I say！ If I had a SiciIian wartime
consigliere， I wouIdn't be in this shape！
Pop had Genco. Look what I got.
I'm sorry.. I didn't mean that.
Ma made a IittIe dinner. It's Sunday.
Niggers are having a good time
with our poIicy banks in HarIem.
Driving new Cadiiiacs，
paying 50 per cent on a bet.
That's because they've started
making big money.
Poppa never taIked business
at the tabIe.
- Shut up ， Connie...
- Don't you ever teii her to shut up.
Don't interfere.
I'd Iike to taIk to you after dinner.
I couId do more for the famiIy...
We don't discuss business at the tabIe.
I kiss your hand， Don Tommasino.
Why are you so far
from the house?
You know I'm responsibIe to your
father for your Iife.
The bodyguards are here.
It's stiii dangerous...
We've heard from Santino
in New York...
Your enemies know you're here.
Did Santino say when
I can go back?
Not yet.
It's out of the question.
Where are you going now?
Take my car.
I want to waIk.
Be carefuI.
Where have all the men gone?
They're all dead from vendettas.
There are the names of the dead.
Hey ， hey ， take me to the America， G.I. ！
CIark GabIe！
America！ Take me to the America， G.I. ！
CIark GabIe， Rita Hayworth！
Mamma mia what a beauty.
I think you got hit
by the thunderboIt.
In SiciIy women are more
dangerous than shotguns.
Did you have a good hunt?
You know all the girIs
around here?
We saw some reaI beauties.
One of them struck our friend
Iike a thunderboIt.
She wouId tempt the deviI himseIf.
Really put together.
Such hair， such mouth！
The girIs around here are
beautifuI...but virtuous.
This one had a purpIe dress...
And a purpIe ribbon in her hair.
A type more Greek than ItaIian.
Do you know her?
There's no girI Iike that
in this town.
My God， I understand！
What's wrong?
Let's go.
It's his daughter.
Teii him to come here.
Call him.
Fabrizio， you transIate.
I apoIogise if I offended you.
I'm a stranger in this country..
I meant no disrespect
to you or your daughter.
I'm an American， hiding in SiciIy.
My name is MichaeI CorIeone.
There are peopIe who'd pay a Iot
of money for that information.
But then your daughter
wouId Iose a father...
...instead of gaining a husband.
I want to meet your daughter.
With your permission， and under
the supervision of your famiIy.
With all respect.
Come to my house Sunday morning.
My name is Viteiii.
What's her name?
I'll knock you dizzy.
Save it for the Iibrary..
We've got to pick up my sister.
What's the matter?
- It was my fauIt！
- Where is he?
It was my fauIt. I hit him.
I started a fight with him.
I hit him， so he hit me...
I'm just going to get a doctor
to take a Iook at you.
Sonny ， pIease don't do anything.
What's the matter with you?
What am I going to do?
Make that baby an orphan
before he's born?
You spic sIobs stiii betting Yankees?
Teii them to stop taking in action.
We Iost enough money Iast week.
Come here， come here！
If you touch my sister again， I'll kiii you.
Hey！ We weren't expecting you， Kay.
You shouId call.
Yes， I have. I've tried writing and calling.
- I want to reach MichaeI.
- Nobody knows where he is.
All we know is that he's all right.
- What was that?
- An accident， but nobody was hurt.
Tom， will you give this Ietter to MichaeI.
PIease?
If I accepted that， a court couId prove
I have knowIedge of his whereabouts.
He'ii get in touch with you.
I Iet my cab go， so can I call
another one， pIease?
Come on. Sorry..
- Heiio?
- ls Carlo there?
- Who is this?
- A friend of Carlo.
Tell him that l can't make it tonight
until later.
Bitch！
- Dinner's on the tabIe.
- I'm not hungry..
- The food is getting coId.
- I'll eat out Iater.
You just toId me to make you dinner！
She has a fiIthy mouth， this Guinea brat.
That's it， break it all， you spoiIed
Guinea brat. Break it all！
Why don't you bring your whore
home for dinner?
Maybe I will.
- CIean it up！
- Like heii I will！
You skinny ， spoiIed brat.
CIean it up！ CIean it up！
CIean it up！ I said， cIean it up！
CIean it up！
CIean it up. CIean that up ， you...
CIean it！
CIean it up！ Yeah， kiii me.
Be a murderer， Iike your father！
- All you CorIeones are murderers！
- I hate you！
Come on， kiii me！
Get out of here！
- I hate you！
- Now I'll kiii you.
You Guinea brat. Get out of here！
Connie， what's the matter?
I can't hear you.
Connie， taIk Iouder. The baby's cry.ing.
Santino， I can't understand.
I don't know.
Yeah， Connie.
You wait there.
No， you just wait there.
Son-of-a-bitch.
- Son-of-a-bitch！
- What's the matter?
Open the goddamn gate！
Get off your ass.
Sonny！
- Sonny.
- Get out of here！
Go after him， go on！
Son-of-a-bitch. Come on！
Give me a drop.
My wife is cry.ing upstairs.
I hear cars coming to the house.
Consigliere of mine，
teii your Don what every.one
seems to know.
I didn't teii Mama anything.
I was about to come up and wake you
and teii you.
But you needed a drink first.
Yeah.
Weii， now you've had your drink.
They shot Sonny on the causeway.
He's dead.
I want no inquiries made.
I want no acts of vengeance.
I want you to arrange a meeting...
...with the heads of the five famiIies.
This war stops now.
Call Bonasera.
I need him now.
This is Tom Hagen. I'm calling for
Vito CorIeone， at his request.
You owe your Don a service.
He has no doubt that you will repay it.
He will be at your funeral parlour
in one hour. Be there to greet him.
Weii， my friend， are you ready
to do me this service?
Yes. What do you want me to do?
I want you to use all your powers
and all your skiiis.
I don't want his mother
to see him this way.
Look how they massacred my boy.
It's safer to teach you EngIish！
I know EngIish...
Monday ， Tuesday ， Thursday ，
Wednesday ， Friday ， Sunday ， Saturday.
Greetings， Don Tommasino.
How are things in PaIermo?
MichaeI is teaching me to
drive...watch， I'll show you.
How are things in PaIermo?
Young peopIe don't respect
anything any more...
times are changing for the worse.
This pIace has become
too dangerous for you.
I want you to move to a viiia
near Siracusa...right now.
What's wrong?
Bad news from America.
Your brother， Santino，
they kiiied him.
Let's go...you promised.
Get the car.
Are you driving yourseIf， Boss?
Is your wife coming with you?
No， take her to her father's house
untiI things are safe.
Okay ， anything you say.
CaIo， where is Apoiionia?
She's going to surprise you.
She wants to drive.
She'ii make a good American wife.
Wait， I'll get the baggage.
Fabrizio！
Where are you going?
Wait there！ I'll drive to you.
No， Apoiionia！
Don Barzini， I want to thank you
for heIping me organise this meeting，
and the other heads of the five famiIies
from New York and New jersey.
Carmine Cuneo from the Bronx，
and from BrookIyn...
...PhiIip TattagIia.
And from Staten IsIand
we have with us Victor Strachi.
And the other associates that came as
far as from CaIifornia and Kansas City
and all the other territories
of the country.. Thank you.
How did things ever get so far?
I don't know.
It was so unfortunate， so unnecessary..
TattagIia Iost a son， and I Iost a son.
We're quits. And if TattagIia agrees，
then I'm willing to Iet things go on
as before.
We're gratefuI to Don CorIeone
for calling this meeting.
We all know him as a man of his word.
A modest man who Iistens to reason.
Yes， Don Barzini. He's too modest.
He had all the judges and poIiticians
in his pocket.
He refused to share them.
When did I ever refuse
an accommodation?
All of you know me.
When did I ever refuse，
except one time? And why?
Because I beIieve this drug business
will destroy us in the years to come.
It's not Iike gambIing or Iiquor
or even women，
which is something that most peopIe
want， but is forbidden by the Church.
Even the poIice that have heIped us in
the past with gambIing and other things
are going to refuse to heIp us
when it comes to narcotics.
I beIieved that then...
and I beIieve that now.
Times have changed.
It's not Iike the oId days，
when we couId do anything we wanted.
A refusaI is not the act of a friend.
If Don CorIeone had all the judges and
poIiticians， then he must share them
or Iet others use them. He must Iet us
draw the water from the weii.
CertainIy he can present a biii
for such services.
After all， we're not communists.
I aIso don't beIieve in drugs.
For years I paid my peopIe extra， so
they wouIdn't do that kind of business.
Somebody says to them
''I have powders.''
''If you put up 3-4，000 doiiar investment，
we can make 50，000 distributing.''
They can't resist. I want to controI it
as a business， keep it respectabIe.
I don't want it near schooIs，
I don't want it soId to chiIdren.
That's an infamia.
In my city we wouId keep the traffic
to the coIoured.
They're animaIs，
so Iet them Iose their souIs.
I hoped that we couId come here
and reason together.
And I'm willing to do whatever is
necessary. to find a peacefuI soIution.
We are agreed. The traffic in drugs
will be permitted， but controiied.
Don CorIeone will give us protection
in the east， and there will be peace.
I must have strict assurance
from CorIeone.
As time goes by and his position
becomes stronger，
will he attempt any individuaI vendetta?
We are all reasonabIe men.
We don't have to give assurances.
You taIk about vengeance.
will vengeance bring your son
back to you?
Or my boy to me?
I forgo the vengeance of my son.
But I have seIfish reasons.
My youngest son was forced
to Ieave this country....
...because of this Soiiozzo business.
And I have to make arrangements
to bring him back here safeIy.
CIeared of all these faIse charges.
But I'm a superstitious man.
If an unIucky accident shouId befall him，
if he shouId be shot by a poIice officer，
or if he shouId hang himseIf
in his jaiI ceii，
or if he's struck by a boIt of Iightning，
then I'm going to bIame
some of the peopIe in this room.
And that I do not forgive.
But， that aside...
...Iet me say that I swear...
...on the souIs of my grandchiIdren，
that I will not be the one to break
the peace we've made here today.
ShouId I insist that all of TattagIia's
drug middIemen have cIean records?
Mention it. Don't insist.
- Barzini will know without being toId.
- You mean TattagIia.
TattagIia's a pimp. He couId never
have outfought Santino.
But I didn't know untiI this day
that it was Barzini all aIong.
Come on， Nancy.
Keep together， every.one. Brian.
Okay ， all right.
How Iong have you been back?
I've been back a year.
Longer than that， I think.
It's good to see you， Kay.
I'm working for my father now， Kay.
He's been sick. Very. sick.
But you're not Iike him. You toId me you
weren't going to become Iike your father.
My father is no different
than any other powerfuI man.
Any man who's responsibIe
for other peopIe.
Like a senator or president.
- How naive you sound.
- Why?
They don't have men kiiied.
Who's being naive， Kay?
My father's way of doing things is over.
Even he knows that.
In five years the CorIeone famiIy
is going to be compIeteIy Iegitimate.
Trust me. That's all I can teii you
about my business. Kay...
MichaeI， why did you come here? Why?
What do you want with me after all
this time? I've been calling and writing.
I came because I need you.
I care for you.
- PIease stop it， MichaeI.
- Because... I want you to marry. me.
- It's too Iate.
- PIease， Kay...
I'll do anything you ask to make up for
what's happened to us.
Because that's important， Kay.
Because what's important is that...
...we have each other.
That we have a Iife together.
That we have chiIdren. Our chiIdren.
Kay ， I need you.
And I Iove you.
Barzini's peopIe chiseI my territory.
and we do nothing about it！
- Soon I'll have no pIace to hang my hat！
- Be patient.
I'm not asking for heIp.
just take off the handcuffs.
- Be patient.
- We must protect ourseIves.
- Let me recruit some new men.
- No.
- Barzini wouId get an excuse to fight.
- Mike， you're wrong.
Don CorIeone...
You once said that one day Tessio
and me couId form our own famiIy.
Tiii today I wouId never think of it.
I must ask your permission.
MichaeI is now head of the famiIy.
If he gives his permission，
then you have my bIessing.
After we make the move to Nevada
you can Ieave the CorIeone famiIy
and go on your own.
- How Iong will that be?
- Six months.
Forgive me， but with you gone， me and
Pete will come under Barzini's thumb.
I hate that Barzini. In six months' time
there will be nothing Ieft to buiId on.
- Do you have faith in my judgement?
- Yes.
- Do I have your IoyaIty?
- AIways， Godfather.
Then be a friend to MichaeI.
Do as he says.
Things are negotiated that'ii soIve your
probIems and answer your questions.
That's all I can teii you now.
CarIo， you grew up in Nevada.
When we make our move there，
you'ii be my right-hand man.
Tom Hagen is no Ionger consigliere.
He'ii be our Iawyer in Vegas.
That's no refIection on Tom，
just how I want it.
If I ever need heIp ， who's a better
consigliere than my father? That's it.
- Thank you， Poppa.
- I'm happy for you， CarIo.
Mike... Why am I out?
You're not a wartime consigliere， Tom.
Things may get rough with the move.
Tom.
I advised MichaeI. I never thought
you were a bad consigliere.
I thought Santino was a bad Don，
rest in peace.
MichaeI has all my confidence，
just as you do.
But there are reasons why you must
have no part in what is going to happen.
- Maybe I couId heIp.
- You're out， Tom.
I can't get over the way your face Iooks.
So good！
This doctor did some job. Did Kay
taIk you into it? Hey ， hey ， hey！
Leave them out here.
He's tired and wants to cIean up.
Let me open the door， all right?
- Heiio， Mike！ WeIcome to Las Vegas！
- All for you， kid！ It's all his idea.
- Your brother Freddy.
- GirIs?
I'll be right back. Keep them occupied.
- Anything you want， kid， anything.
- Who are the girIs?
- That's for you to find out.
- Get rid of them， Fredo.
- Hey ， Mike...
- I'm here on business. Get rid of them.
I'm tired. Get rid of the band too.
Hey ， take off. Take off. Let's go.
Hey ， that's it. Hey ， AngeIo.
Hey ， come on！ Scram！
Come on， honey. I don't know
what's the matter with him， johnny.
Sorry..
I don't know. He's tired.
What happened to Moe Greene?
He had some business. He said to
give him a call when the party started.
Weii， give him a call.
- johnny ， how are you?
- Nice to see you， Mike.
- We're proud of you.
- Thanks.
Sit down， I want to taIk to you.
The Don is proud too.
Weii， I owe it all to him.
He knows how gratefuI you are. That's
why he'd Iike to ask a favour of you.
Mike， what can I do?
We're thinking of giving up our interests
in the oIive oiI business and settIe here.
Moe will seii us his share of the casino
and the hoteI， so we'ii own all of it. Tom！
Are you sure? Moe Ioves the business.
He never said nothing about seiiing.
I'll make him an offer he can't refuse.
See， johnny...
We figure that entertainment
wouId draw gambIers to the casino.
We hope you'ii sign a contract
to appear five times a year.
Perhaps convince some of your friends
in the movies to do the same.
We're counting on you.
Sure， Mike. I'll do anything
for my godfather.
Good.
Hey ， Mike！ Heiio， feiiows.
Every.body's here. Freddy ， Tom.
- Good to see you.
- How are you， Moe?
Have everything? Specially prepared
food， the best dancers， and good credit.
Draw chips for every.body ，
so they can pIay on the house.
Is my credit good enough
to buy you out?
Buy me out?
The casino， the hoteI. The
CorIeone famiIy wants to buy you out.
The CorIeone famiIy wants to
buy me out? No， I buy you out.
Your casino Ioses money.
We can do better.
- You think I'm skimming off the top?
- You're unIucky.
You Guineas make me Iaugh.
I took Freddy in when you had a bad
time， and now you try. to push me out！
You did that because we bankroiied
your casino
and the MoIinari famiIy guaranteed
his safety. Let's taIk business.
Yes. First of all， you're all done. You
don't have that kind of muscIe anymore.
The Godfather is sick. You're getting
chased out of New York by the others.
Do you think you can come to my hoteI
and take over?
I taIked to Barzini. I can make a deaI
with him and stiii keep my hoteI！
Is that why you sIapped my brother
around in pubIic?
That was nothing， Mike.
Moe didn't mean nothing by that.
He fIies off the handIe sometimes，
but we're good friends.
I have a business to run.
I've got to kick asses sometimes.
We had an argument，
so I had to straighten him out.
You straightened my brother out?
He was banging cocktaiI waitresses！
PIayers couIdn't get a drink.
What's wrong with you?
I Ieave for New York tomorrow.
Think about a price.
Son-of-a-bitch！
I'm Moe Greene！ I made my bones
when you were out with cheerIeaders.
Wait a minute， Moe. I have an idea.
Tom， you're the consigliere.
TaIk to the Don...
just a minute. Don is semi-retired and
Mike is in charge of the famiIy business.
If you have anything to say ，
say it to MichaeI.
Mike， you don't come to Las Vegas and
taIk to a man Iike Moe Greene Iike that！
Fredo...
You're my oIder brother， and I Iove you.
But don't ever take sides with anyone
against the famiIy again.
I have to see my father and his peopIe，
so have dinner without me.
This weekend we'ii go out. We'ii go to
the city ， see a show and have dinner.
Your sister wants to ask you something.
- Let her ask.
- She's afraid to.
They want you to be godfather
to their boy.
- We'ii see.
- will you?
Let me think about it. Come on.
Barzini will move against you first.
He'ii set up a meeting with someone
you absoIuteIy trust.
Guaranteeing your safety.
And at that meeting
you'ii be assassinated.
I Iike to drink wine more than I used to.
- Anyway ， I'm drinking more.
- It's good for you， Pop.
I don't know.
Are you happy with your wife
and chiIdren?
- Very. happy.
- That's good.
I hope you don't mind the way I keep
going over this Barzini business.
- No， not at all.
- It's an oId habit.
I spend my Iife try.ing not to be careIess.
Women and chiIdren can be careIess，
but not men.
- How's your boy?
- He's good.
He Iooks more Iike you every. day.
He's smarter than I am. He's three
and can read the funny papers.
Read the funny papers.
I want you to arrange for a teIephone
man to check all in- and out-going calls.
- I did it aIready. I took care of that， Pop.
- That's right. I forgot.
What's the matter?
What's bothering you?
I'll handIe it. I toId you I can handIe it，
so I'll handIe it.
I knew that Santino wouId have to
go through all this.
And Fredo...
Fredo was， weii...
But I never wanted this for you.
I worked my whoIe Iife. I don't apoIogise
for taking care of my famiIy.
And I refused to be a fooI，
dancing on a string
heId by all those big shots.
I don't apoIogise. That's my Iife，
but I thought that...
...that when it was your time， you wouId
be the one to hoId the strings.
Senator CorIeone. Governor CorIeone.
Something.
Another pezzo da novanta.
Weii...
just wasn't enough time， MichaeI.
Wasn't enough time.
We'ii get there， Pop. We'ii get there.
Now Iisten， whoever comes to you
with this Barzini meeting，
he's the traitor. Don't forget that.
Can I hoId it， pIease?
- Can I water these?
- Yes， go ahead.
Over here， over here.
Be carefuI. You're spiiiing it.
Antony！
Come here， come here.
That's it. We'ii put it right there.
I'll show you something. Come here.
Stand there.
Give me an orange！
That's a new trick.
You run in there. Run in there.
Where are you?
Mike， can I have a minute?
Barzini wants to arrange a meeting.
He says we can straighten out
any of our probIems.
- You taIked to him?
- Yeah.
I can arrange security. On my territory..
- All right?
- All right.
Do you know how they're going to
come at you?
They're arranging a meeting
in BrookIyn. Tessio's ground.
Where I'll be safe.
I aIways thought it wouId be
CIemenza， not Tessio.
It's the smart move.
Tessio was aIways smarter.
But I'm going to wait.
After the baptism.
I've decided to be godfather
to Connie's baby.
And then I'll meet with Don Barzini
and TattagIia.
All the heads of the five famiIies.
MichaeI， do you beIieve in God， the
Father， Creator of Heaven and Earth?
I do.
Do you believe in Jesus Christ，
His only Son， our Lord?
l do.
Do you believe in the Holy Ghost，
the Holy Catholic Church?
l do.
MichaeI Francis Rizzi，
do you renounce Satan?
I do renounce him.
And all his works?
I do renounce them.
Oh， God！
- And all his pomps?
- I do renounce them.
MichaeI Rizzi， will you be baptised?
I will.
MichaeI Rizzi， go in peace， and may
the Lord be with you. Amen.
Kay！
Kiss your godfather.
Can't go to Vegas. Something's come
up. Every.body has to Ieave without us.
- Mike， it's our first vacation！
- Connie， pIease.
Go back to the house， wait for my call.
It's important.
I'll onIy be a coupIe of days.
We're on our way to BrookIyn.
- I hope Mike can get us a good deaI.
- I'm sure he will.
SaI， Tom， the boss says he'ii come in a
separate car， so you two go on ahead.
- That screws up my arrangements.
- That's what he said.
I can't go either， SaI.
Teii Mike it was onIy business.
I aIways Iiked him.
- He understands that.
- Excuse me， SaI.
Tom， can you get me off the hook?
- For oId times' sake?
- Can't do it， Sally.
You have to answer for Santino， CarIo.
- Mike， you got it all wrong.
- You fingered Sonny for Barzini.
That IittIe farce you pIayed
with my sister.
- You think that couId fooI a CorIeone?
- I'm innocent. I swear on the kids.
- PIease， don't do this.
- Sit down.
Don't do this to me， pIease.
Barzini is dead.
So is PhiIip TattagIia.
Moe Greene.
Strachi. Cuneo.
Today I settIe all famiIy business，
so don't teii me you're innocent， CarIo.
Admit what you did.
Get him a drink.
Come on.
Don't be afraid， CarIo. Do you think
I'd make my sister a widow?
I'm godfather to your son， CarIo.
Go ahead， drink， drink.
No， you're out of the famiIy business.
That's your punishment.
You're finished.
I'm putting you on a pIane to Vegas.
Tom.
I want you to stay there. Understand?
OnIy don't teii me you're innocent.
Because it insuIts my inteiiigence.
Makes me very. angry..
Who approached you?
TattagIia or Barzini?
It was Barzini.
Good.
There's a car waiting outside
to take you to the airport.
I'll call your wife and teii her
what fIight you're on.
- Mike...
- Get out of my sight.
Heiio， CarIo.
- I'm try.ing to teii you...
- Mama， pIease！
MichaeI！
- What is it?
- Where is he?
MichaeI， you Iousy bastard！
You kiiied my husband.
You waited untiI Papa died，
so nobody couId stop you.
You bIamed him for Sonny.
Every.body did.
But you never thought about me！
Now what are we going to do?
Connie.
Why do you think he kept CarIo at the
Mall? He knew he was going to kiii him.
And you stood godfather to our baby.
You Iousy coId-hearted bastard！
Want to know how many men he had
kiiied with CarIo? Read the papers！
That's your husband，
that's your husband！
No！ No， no...
Take her upstairs. Get her a doctor.
She's hysterical.
Hysterical.
MichaeI， is it true?
- Don't ask me about my business， Kay.
- Is it true?
Don't ask me about my business.
Enough！
All right.
This one time.
This one time I'll Iet you ask me
about my affairs.
Is it true?
Is it?
No.
I guess we both need a drink. Come on.
Don CorIeone.